<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Bad at all of this (Posts about disruption)</title><link>https://stevelle.me/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://stevelle.me/categories/disruption.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 22:56:23 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Context Switch</title><link>https://stevelle.me/posts/context-switch/</link><dc:creator>Steve Lewis</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is a mixed blessing to have multiple folks pinging for my attention at the
same time. On the one hand it suggests that I am viewed as an asset to the
community, but on the other it can wreck my basic productivity as I try to keep
up with the daily work of code reviews and testing, and sometimes even writing
code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a moment this week where I was working with three different people at the
same time, spanning three different project teams. The conversations lasted from
approximately five and twenty minutes each with significant overlap. One
involved spot checking a change, another involved call trace analysis, and the
third involved a failure without a clear place to begin diagnosing. The context
switching was a challenge, but I am getting better at that over time. That
becomes a key bit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Context switching is a skill, and we can improve with practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't know what the greater cost of that practice is however. Obviously, that
is the enough of a disruption to break any sense of &lt;cite&gt;flow&lt;/cite&gt; but does it take
longer to get back into the groove after a longer context switching event than
from a 5 minute context switch? How about adding two new contexts? I'm not sure
it matters, in my case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The value of getting three other folks overcome their barriers is likely to be
significantly more valuable than the alternative. This is something that has
become easier for me to see over time. First, I know I don't work at anything
like 10x what my peers do. Secondly, the value of having progress on multiple
fronts at the same time is far more valuable to OpenStack than having one
fix merged faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of that is due to OpenStack having 2 releases per year, and the operator
community tending to trail well behing the latest release of OpenStack. It's not
like this bug fix or feature work is going to actually get widely deployed
faster simply because it was merged one day earlier. Secondly, OpenStack is huge
and complex, which means one feature or fix is not likely to have a large
impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, in this context, the greater value is to unblock three other people, who can
then build their understanding and in turn pass that on to others who follow.
The superior outcome is to hedge our efforts across many features and bugs and
those which make the cut for the next release will stand collectively. So I
accept the interruptions without reservation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>communication</category><category>disruption</category><guid>https://stevelle.me/posts/context-switch/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 02:21:25 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>