<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Bad at all of this (Posts about thinkings)</title><link>https://stevelle.me/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://stevelle.me/categories/thinkings.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 23:24:15 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Learning As Performance, part 1</title><link>https://stevelle.me/posts/learning-as-performance-1/</link><dc:creator>Steve Lewis</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let's talk about performance reviews &lt;a class="footnote-reference" href="https://stevelle.me/posts/learning-as-performance-1/#id4" id="id1"&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;. Consistently, performance reviews
have been uncomfortable for me. I feel awkward about the standard questions used
in reviews and in self-assessments and don't want to go through the process
because there will always be some uncomfortable moments in there which would be
easier to not revisit. Yet they remain a common feature of almost all
organizations of any size and they keep happening so if performance is going to
be reviewed, I would like to make it meaningful. What should "performance" mean
then, and what does it suggest about my career advancement?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-problem-with-performance"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Problem with Performance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a coder, my performance could take the form of having done some body of work.
Let's say I built some features and I fixed some bugs. This is the 'what' of the
work. Should you gauge my performance by the particular work done? Then we must
ask more questions: How did the work I completed get selected? Did I choose
politically sensitive work to garner recognition and did I appear to succeed in
the work of did the value of the work under perform expectations? All of this
can be corrupted by independant variables and any measure can be gamed which
means instead of measuring my performance you are effectively measuring the
weather.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For piece-work jobs this may be "good enough" but for knowledge workers the
organization's primary metrics might not be what the best criteria to gague
individual performance. For knowledge workers to keep your organization growing
and to accelerate that growth to keep ahead of competitors you need their
productivity to grow over time. The difficult fact is that given the
increasing cost of maintaining software over time as feature bloat, technical
debt, and code rot set in often causes a slowing of productivity &lt;a class="footnote-reference" href="https://stevelle.me/posts/learning-as-performance-1/#id5" id="id2"&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;. This
makes it even more dangerous for your knowledge workers to be just treading
water. Learning is obligatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another measure of the value of my work in an organization is in 'how' I did the
work. I'd like to suggest that how I do the work, specifically what I learned
from doing the work, is a better indicator of performance and value to the
organization. This could be a basis for performance review and considering
recognition for achievements (and if your org does titles maybe this can be
valuable in marking advancement in titles too &lt;a class="footnote-reference" href="https://stevelle.me/posts/learning-as-performance-1/#id6" id="id3"&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="learning-as-performance"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Learning as Performance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the rewards of working on software is that there are a lot of
opportunities to solve new problems all the time --variety! A former coworker
once observed (I paraphrase) that our job is to be struggling, to be challenged.
As soon as we overcome one challenge, there is another one waiting for us and
it's time to move on to that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are going to spend the great majority of our time struggling through that
next thing. We can mark our professional development in part by our raw
productivity, but the greater part of our professional growth comes from the
breakthroughs: the monster bugs fixed or the finesse of implementing a feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If my daily routine is going to be one continuous learning process, and that
learning is the function by which I increase my technical capabilities and
productivity, then this is a fair measure of my increasing value as an employee
to the organization. If my organization values individual capability and
productivity increasing, let's think about how we can reflect that in setting
career paths, marking individual and team achievements, and conducting
performance reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What could be gained by looking at reviews through the lense of learnings?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By including, or centering on, learned lessons in performance reviews we can
discuss all of our work in non-threatening terms; finding insights and lessons
and discoveries rather than letting the hard times be seen as oversights,
failures, or mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next part I will explore ways to recognize and keep track of the
individual learnings so they are available at performance review time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;table class="docutils footnote" frame="void" id="id4" rules="none"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col class="label"&gt;&lt;col&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="label"&gt;&lt;a class="fn-backref" href="https://stevelle.me/posts/learning-as-performance-1/#id1"&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Performance_appraisal"&gt;Wikipedia, Performance Appraisal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table class="docutils footnote" frame="void" id="id5" rules="none"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col class="label"&gt;&lt;col&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="label"&gt;&lt;a class="fn-backref" href="https://stevelle.me/posts/learning-as-performance-1/#id2"&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://static1.1.sqspcdn.com/static/f/702523/9243601/1288747638857/200712-Jones.pdf"&gt;"Geriatric Issues of Aging Software" by Casper Jones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table class="docutils footnote" frame="void" id="id6" rules="none"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col class="label"&gt;&lt;col&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="label"&gt;&lt;a class="fn-backref" href="https://stevelle.me/posts/learning-as-performance-1/#id3"&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://randsinrepose.com/archives/titles-are-toxic/"&gt;Rands in Repose blog: Titles are Toxic:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>performance_management</category><category>thinkings</category><guid>https://stevelle.me/posts/learning-as-performance-1/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 03:25:51 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>